Ben Chaplin

Full Stack Web Developer, Software Developer, Web Designer

Park City, UT
(440) 251-8038
bchaplin525@gmail.com
Github: Plaindemon
React Portfolio

PROJECTS

<u>Happy Puppy Adventures</u> — Small Business Webpage

Website created for a small dog daycare business

Routes — MERN SPA Capstone Project

Application for searching up locations & meet friends to hike, bike, or ski with

Randonnee — Interactive FullStack Project

Climbing database that gives users score and then matches them with other climbers

WORK HISTORY

Rover, UT — Rover Dog Daycare

MAY 2017 - PRESENT

- Grew a successful small business with over 30 clients within few months time
- Accumulated a 5 star customer satisfaction rate with over ten profile reviews
- Maintained long term customers using high quality communication services, photo updates, and quick response time

Ken Garff, SLC, UT — Sales & Leasing Specialist

MAY 2019 - APRIL 2020

- Increased individual sales progressively each month by 20%
- Collaborated with a team of 15 people to increase departments sales above goals consistently each month
- Created returning clients and lifetime customers by using quality service and communication skills

Michael Kors, Park City, UT — Full Time Sales & Stock Associate

MAY 2016 - AUGUST 2018

- Created innovative backroom organization for quick refilling and easy inventory management of new products
- Each month I individually sold between 30-40% of the stores monthly sales
- Top 3 in sales performance every month throughout my two years at the store
- Created displays to increase the sales of both new and old product in the store

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, Javascript ES6+ Angular, NoSQL, MongoDB, Hanldebars.js, , Typescript, Github, Express.js, jQuery, CSS3, Git, React, Bootstrap, SQL, MySQL, Node.js, Firebase, Oauth2, Render, Heroku, Wordpress, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, SASS and more

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with experience in HTML, javascript, react as well as experience outside the web development field in anthropology, psychology, science such as biology and chemistry, as well as experience in sales, customer service, art/ceramics and many other fields.

EDUCATION

University of Utah, SLC, UT — Certificate

AUGUST 2021 - MARCH 2022

Full Stack Web Development program that taught the fundamentals of MERN SPA

Utah State University, Logan, UT — Bachelor's Degree

AUGUST 2013 - MAY 2019

Bachelor's of Science with emphasis in Biology & Chemistry & Minor Of Anthropology